<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Notes and Stuff</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Notes and Stuff</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Civil society in Turkey</title>
      <link>/post/2016-11-10-jenny_b_white/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-11-10-jenny_b_white/</guid>
      <description>Reference: article from (Hann and Dunn 1996)
Jenny B. White’s argument is that civic cultures exist in Turkey on a community level that precedes and upon which social movements build their networks.
She also compare these “informal” community ties and political space to the more regulated organizations, arguing that the former are usually left behind in academic literature and therefore seriously understudied and under-represented.
Two main problematic points come out by overcoming this misrepresentation, firstly we can see that civil society might be possible in Islamic countries and, as a cosequence for this, that a democratizing discourse is possible in Islam based cultures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contesting Benevolence</title>
      <link>/post/2016-10-29-tugal-aid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-10-29-tugal-aid/</guid>
      <description>Reference: (Tuğal 2013)
In Tugal’s view the double movement as expressed by Polanyi is a continuous struggle between hegemonic powers and counter hegemony that contraposes market economy and social groups, in his analysis conducted in sultanbeyli he sees how excluded strata of society get included in power relations based on clientelism in the act of realizing a passive revolution, pushing forward this interpretation he then analyzes benevolent associations to understand if and how these are part of the same cooptation by hegemonic powers or are part of the counter movement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influenze turche nella poesia persiana di inizio 1900</title>
      <link>/post/2015-04-03-shahriyar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015-04-03-shahriyar/</guid>
      <description>Introduzione Scopo di questo saggio è presentare un’approfondimento sulle influenze turche nella poesia persiana, in particolare a partire dall’inizio del 1900, e mostrare come la particolarità dell’area azera, un’enclave turcofona in territorio persiano, le abbia permesso di svolgere un ruolo di collegamento sia con le innovazioni socio-culturali sviluppatesi nell’impero Ottomano 1 che con le influenze europee soprattutto in ambito letterario e politico.
Come vedremo più approfonditamente in seguito non solo la vicinanza linguistica ma anche la presenza di uno spirito nazionalista che rivendicava indipendenza per la popolazione azera fornirono un terreno fertile per idee cosiddette moderniste che innovarono la produzione letteraria sia dal punto di vista formale che a livello di contenuti.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note e Appunti per Tesi</title>
      <link>/post/2015-03-06-note_tesi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015-03-06-note_tesi/</guid>
      <description>La non nascita della coscienza di classe in Turchia egemonia tramite soft power: il caso delle vakif un approccio di sociologia storica e etnografia Progetti antropopoietici in Turchia???
Come in un contesto dove la pratica della “sussidiarietà” è storicamente ben affermata si svolga il processo antropopoietico, studio di come la promozione di queste pratiche diviene funzionale nella produzione di individui “egemonizzati” dal discorso politico del partito
 Il ruolo della sadaqa nel discorso politico dell’AKP e il suo utilizzo nel prevenire la formazione di coscienza di classe</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes from Democracy and Social Capital</title>
      <link>/post/2016-10-27-democracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-10-27-democracy/</guid>
      <description>Reference: [@warren_democracy_1999]: Democracy and social capital by Eric M. Uslaner
The concept of trust is central in a prosperous Democracy as it is a preminent part of what Putnam defined as social capital, and in Uslaner’s conceptualization is important as it sets moral values that are precurors of civic networks and social connectedness. Trust leads to cooperation by pushing people to behave morally and develop feelings of reciprocity to each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solidarity among strangers</title>
      <link>/post/2016-11-03-solidarity-bugra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-11-03-solidarity-bugra/</guid>
      <description>Reference: (Candas and Bugra 2010)
Shifting policies of solidarity are what the authors want to investigate in this paper: from a model of national identity based on the concept of turkishness to one based on the (supposedly) more encompassing religious identity of being sunni muslims. If the former posed the basis for the long lasting conflictual contrast of turkishness vs kurdishness, the latter looks more inclusive in its nature, based on the idea of islamic solidarity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Labour Unions in Turkey’s Passive Revolution</title>
      <link>/post/2016-11-06-unions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2016-11-06-unions/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The significant role of social movements for the democratization discourse is mainly due to their ability to play the role of watchdog regarding government’s activities. In particular for its ability to reveal governance practices not compatible to the rule of law and to help manage and prevent dissent. The degree of organizational solidarity between the actors of the civil sphere is a main factor in predicting their relative strength and therefore its freedom of acting and confronting the state in the political sphere.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>